# **Kebin Wang**

Software Engineer Lead — Cloud

## **Profile**

Versatile software engineer with over 14 years of experience building back-end services and front-end applications for multiple domains, for on-promises and cloud-based. Capabilities and experience range from deep technical knowledge designing and developing software applications to managing local and offshore teams in the creation and maintenance of software products.

## **Skills**

Golang, C#, .NET Framework, C++, Java, Python, MySQL, MSSQL, AWS, S3, ECS, EKS, K9S, Micro Service, RestAPI, Swagger Web API, GORM, GraphQL, gqlgen, MySQL, MariaDB, Visual Studio, Docker, Git, CI/CD, DUNS, Experian, PACER

## **Education**

## Ph.D. in Computer Science Boston University

Boston, MA 2003-2009

Focused on Algorithm and Advanced Data Structures

# **Professional Experience**

2021.10 - 2023.11 LSQ (Remote)

## **Legal Entity Project**

- Designed and implemented the project to manage and serve client information on the cloud.
- It is used to remove redundancy, share, and resolve conflicting client info among separated business modules each with localized client data.
- Using Golang and MySQL, implemented realtime services to ingest client info from services, deduplicate, then serve to other services and various clients via RestAPI (using swagger) and GraphQL(via gqlgen), inbound and outbound data services, and a data migration tool.

#### LSQ Credit Engine Upgrade

- Credit Engine uses third party data to evaluate corporate credibilities.
- Designed and implemented the migration of corporation information source from Experian to Dun & Bradstreet.
- Designed the migration of Python serviceless functions in ECS into EKS micro services.
- Worked with Python 3 in AWS ECS serviceless function and AWS ECS.

#### **Corporate Agency Project**

- Designed and implemented the project of centralizing management of detailed corporation info from Dun & Bradstreet, Experian, and other third parties.
- Gathered data from different locations including AWS S3, local database, and locally shared files from different locations.
- Unified data into DB tables.
- Added RESTApi and GraphQL services for data retrievals and updates.

#### LSQ PACER Service

- PACER is a public API for US court records.
- Designed and implemented the project to replace manual query by compliance officers with a service to batch requests via API, removed redundant queries, and saved data into DB.
- Project was designed, implemented, and tested in two weeks.

## **Payment Matching**

- Matching multiple invoices with single money transfer via Quadratic Greedy algorithm and Branch and Bound. Software Engineer Le
- Implemented in Golang and was able to handle 100+ invoices.

#### FIX cache export tool

- Came up with the idea from an internal innovation challenge, designed and implemented a proof of concept.
- FIX services caches contain data not available in DB. This project added a button to OMS client to be able to export all intermediate caches of all FIX services.

#### **Legacy Code Migration projects**

- · Worked in a team to migrate several legacy logic to utilize services for more manageable business logic and better maintainability.
- Migrated legacy Delphi code into C#. Moved most client-side business logic and DB access to centralized services.

#### Mifid II Enhancement project

- Mifid II was a new EU legislative framework to regulate financial markets, which requires
- Worked on the project to enhance FIX services to manage customizable configurations and handle customized communication via FIX message.

#### List Trader project

- Lead the project with one sub-team in US and another in Beijing in Agile approach.
- Redesign and implement a batch trade management and execution module.
- Project will finished as scheduled despite distractions:
  - Team member left for other opportunities,
  - Heavy unexpected client support, sometimes takes more than 50% of a sprint.
  - I managed defense at the same time for a while.
- Implemented in C# and SQL.

#### Multi-Day Order Project

- Lead the project of supporting multiday orders processing and management in the Eze trading and management system.
- Used Agile approach, meet regularly with PM and remote team members for design and implementation.
- Implemented in C# and MSSQL.

#### The Pause/Resume project

- Added Pause/Resume functionalities to multiple core services.
- Designed and implemented Pause/Resume handling mechanisms in various services.
- Had intensive meetings with product owners.
- Achieved good quality -Only one bug was discovered by QA for this multimonths project.

## The New Order Creation project

- Added a new business workflow of handling trading messages.
- Added new business logics, DB synchronizations, new SQL stored procedures.
- Implemented in C# and SQL.

## The .Net Framework, Visual Studio and DevExpress upgrade project

- The project involves tens of solutions and thousands of projects.
- Upgraded for DOT NET framework (2.0 to 4.0) and Visual Studio (2005 to 2010).
- Upgraded customized DevExpress from version 6 to version 10 and added supports for DOT NET version 4.

#### The Symbol Length Extending project

- Eze used to use 16 characters in DB and code for a trading symbol. This project is to expand it to 256 characters in the system.
- ullet Changes included 100+ DB tables being updated. Many Delphi files being updated, and some C# code being updated.

#### **General Work**

- · Work closely with Product Support Group, PM and QA in troubleshooting and solving product issues quickly.
- Help team members and other developers in product setup, configuration, and trouble shooting.

# 2010 - present

#### Some Personal Fun Projs

## kbds

- This is a tool I use to remove duplicate files. It pulls all files info into a MySQL table for easy search and duplication detection.
- Planned features: To be in sync with file system, and a client for file/folder comparison and operation.

#### subset sum

- The problem: the input are a set of positive integers and a target positive integer. Where either some numbers from the input sum to the target, or no solution.
- A fun continuingb work on this NP-Complete problem.